Okay. Hi everyone, uh, let's get started.
好的。大家好，呃，让我们开始吧。
Um, so Chris is traveling this week so he's not here.
嗯，所以克里斯本周旅行，所以他不在这里。
But I'm very excited to say that today we've got
但我很高兴地说今天我们有了
Margaret Mitchell who is a Senior Research Scientist at Google AI.
Margaret Mitchell是Google AI的高级研究科学家。
She's going to tell us about, uh, the latest
她会告诉我们，呃，最新消息
work defining and understanding and improving
工作定义，理解和改进
the situation with bias in artificial intelligence.
人工智能偏见的情况。
Uh, Margaret has a background working in NLP and deep learning,
呃，玛格丽特有一个从事NLP和深度学习的背景，
so I'm really interested to hear what she has to say today. Take it away.
所以我真的很想知道她今天要说些什么。把它拿开。
Great, thank you. Um, can you guys hear me okay?
太好了谢谢。嗯，你们能听见我吗？
I'm not sure if this mic is exactly picking up my voice,
我不确定这个麦克风是不是正在拾起我的声音，
everything's cool? Okay, cool.
一切都很酷？好的，很酷。
Um, so this work is, uh,
嗯，所以这项工作是，呃，
the product of a ton of different people and
大量不同的人和产品
collaborators that I've tried to put up here.
我试图在这里提出的合作者。
Um, some students at Stanford also Johns Hopkins, Google,
嗯，斯坦福大学的一些学生也是约翰霍普金斯大学，谷歌，
Facebook and Microsoft are all represented, cool.
Facebook和微软都代表着酷炫。
So, um, for those of you who haven't seen the set of slides before,
所以，嗯，对于那些之前没有看过幻灯片的人，
what do you see here? Just shout it out.
你在这看到什么？只是喊出来。
Bananas.
香蕉。
Bananas. Okay what else?
香蕉。好的还有什么？
Stickers.
贴纸。
Stickers. What else?
贴纸。还有什么？
[NOISE] Shelves. What else?
[NOISE]货架。还有什么？
Bunches of bananas.
一束香蕉。
Bunches of bananas. What else?
一束香蕉。还有什么？
Yellow, ripe bananas.
黄色，成熟的香蕉。
You said ripe bananas, good.
你说成熟的香蕉，好。
So you can add [LAUGHTER] bananas with stickers on them.
所以你可以添加[笑声]香蕉贴上它们。
You can start doing, like, embedded clauses, you know,
你可以开始做，比如，嵌入式条款，你知道，
bunches of bananas with stickers on them on shelves in the store to get, kinda, crazy.
一堆香蕉贴在他们在商店的货架上得到，有点，疯狂。
But we don't tend to say yellow bananas, right?
但我们不倾向于说黄香蕉，对吗？
So given something like this,
所以给出这样的东西，
we might say green bananas or we might say unripe bananas.
我们可能会说绿色香蕉或者我们可能会说未成熟的香蕉。
Given an image like this we might say ripe bananas or,
鉴于这样的图像我们可能会说成熟的香蕉，或者，
uh, bananas with spots on them.
呃，香蕉上有斑点。
Uh, if you're me, you might say bananas that are good for banana bread.
呃，如果你是我，你可能会说香蕉对香蕉面包有好处。
Um, but given an image like this or something like this in the real world,
嗯，但在现实世界中给出了像这样或类似的图像，
we tend not to mention the yellowness.
我们倾向于不提黄色。
And the reason for this is because yellow is prototypical for bananas.
其原因在于黄色是香蕉的原型。
So the idea of prototypes, uh,
所以原型的想法，呃，
stems from prototype theory which goes back to the early '70s,
源于原型理论，可追溯到70年代初，
uh, coming out of the work of Eleanor Rosch and colleagues.
呃，从埃莉诺罗什及其同事的工作中走出来。
Um, and it's this idea that there are
嗯，这就是这个想法
some stored central prototypical notions of objects,
一些存储的中心原型对象概念，
um, that we access as we're operating,
嗯，我们在操作时访问，
uh, throughout the world.
呃，遍布全世界。
There's some disagreement about whether these prototypes are
关于这些原型是否存在，存在一些分歧
actual exemplars of objects or something like a distribution over what's likely,
对象的实际样本或类似于可能的分布的东西，
but there is general agreement that we do have some, sort of,
但人们普遍认为我们确实有一些，
sense of what's typical and what's a typical of the things in
什么是典型的，什么是典型的东西
the world and we tend to notice and talk about the things that are atypical.
世界，我们倾向于注意和谈论非典型的事物。
Um, so this is a riddle that I
嗯，所以这是我的谜语
heard in middle school that worked a little bit more at that time,
在中学听说当时工作多了一点，
um, some of you might have heard it before.
嗯，有些人可能以前听过。
A man and his son are in
一个男人和他的儿子在
a terrible accident and are rushed to the hospital in critical care.
一场可怕的事故，被送往医院接受重症监护。
The doctor looks at the boy and exclaims,
医生看着那个男孩惊呼，
"I can't operate on this boy,
“我不能操这个男孩，
he's my son," How could this be? [NOISE].
他是我的儿子，“这怎么可能？[NOISE]。
Two dads?
两个爸爸？
Two dads or he has a mum who's a doctor, right.
两个爸爸或者他妈妈是医生，对吧。
Otherwise known as a female doctor,
否则称为女医生，
which might be contracted- contrasted with doctor.
可能与医生形成对比。
Um, in a study they did,
嗯，在他们做的一项研究中，
uh, when they first, sort of,
呃，当他们第一次，有点
put forward this riddle at Boston University,
在波士顿大学提出这个谜题，
they found that the majority of test subjects
他们发现大多数考试科目
overlooked the possibility that the doctor could be a she.
忽视了医生可能成为她的可能性。
And that included men, women and self-described feminists.
其中包括男人，女人和自我描述的女权主义者。
So the point is that,
所以重点是，
these, kinds of, uh,
这些，各种，呃，
ways of talking about things and assumptions that we make,
谈论我们做的事情和假设的方式，
aren't necessarily something that speaks to a negative intent,
不一定是负面意图，
but something that speaks to how we actually store representations in
但是有些东西可以说明我们如何实际存储表示
our minds and how we access those representations as we interact,
我们的思想以及我们在互动时如何访问这些表示，
uh, in the world.
呃，在这个世界上。
So this, uh, this affects what we can learn when we're learning from text.
所以这，呃，这影响了我们从文本中学习时可以学到的东西。
So, um, this is work from 2013,
所以，嗯，这是2013年的工作，
where they took a look at what was, sort of,
他们在哪里看看是什么，有点像，
most likely, what would you learn if you were just learning from raw text,
最有可能的是，如果你只是从原始文本中学习，你会学到什么，
um, what were some things that were common in the world?
嗯，这世界上常见的事情是什么？
Um, they found that in this setup
嗯，他们发现在这个设置中
something like murdering was ten times more likely than blinking.
像谋杀这样的东西比眨眼的可能性高十倍。
And the reason for this is because people tend
其原因在于人们倾向于此
not to mention these typical things that go without saying.
更不用说这些不言而喻的典型事物了。
We don't tend to mention things like blinking and breathing,
我们不倾向于提及眨眼和呼吸等事情，
but we do mention atypical events like murder and that affects the, kind of,
但是我们确实提到了像谋杀这样的非典型事件，这会影响到，
things a machine can learn from texts that we put out in the world,
机器可以从我们在世界上发布的文本中学到的东西，
because it's been subject to all of
因为它受到了所有人的影响
these filtering processes that we have as humans before we, uh, communicate.
在我们之前，我们作为人类进行的这些过滤过程，呃，沟通。
Um, this issue in particular is known as Human Reporting Bias.
嗯，这个问题特别被称为人类报告偏见。
Which is that the frequency with which people write
这就是人们写作的频率
about actions, outcomes or properties,
关于行动，结果或财产，
is not a reflection of real-world frequencies or
不是现实世界频率的反映
the degree to which a property is characteristic of a class of individuals,
财产是一类人的特征的程度，
but says a lot more about how we're actually
但更多关于我们的实际情况
processing the world and what we think is remarkable.
处理世界和我们认为非凡的东西。
So this affects everything a system can learn.
所以这会影响系统可以学习的一切。
Um, in a typical machine learning paradigm,
嗯，在一个典型的机器学习范例中，
one of the first steps is to collect and potentially annotate training data.
最初的步骤之一是收集并可能注释培训数据。
From there a model can be trained,
从那里可以训练模型，
uh, from there, uh,
呃，从那里，呃，
media can be filtered rank- ranked, aggregated,
媒体可以过滤排名，汇总，
generated in some way,
以某种方式产生，
um, and from there people see the output.
嗯，从那里人们看到输出。
And we like to think of this as a relatively straightforward pipeline,
我们认为这是一个相对简单的管道，
um, but at the very start, uh,
嗯，但是从一开始，呃，
even before we're collecting the data,
甚至在我们收集数据之前
actually within the data itself,
实际上在数据本身内，
are a host of different kinds of human biases.
是一系列不同类型的人类偏见。
So things like stereotyping, things like prejudice,
所以像陈规定型观念，偏见之类的东西，
things like racism and that's embedded within the data before we collect it.
像种族主义之类的东西，在我们收集之前嵌入数据中。
Then as we collect and annotate data,
然后，当我们收集和注释数据时，
further biases become introduced.
进一步的偏见被引入。
So things like sampling errors, confirmation bias, um,
所以像抽样错误，确认偏见，嗯，
uh, in-group bias and out-group bias and I'll talk about these,
呃，群内偏见和外群体偏见，我会谈论这些，
um, a little bit.
嗯，一点点。
Oh, and I should mention feel free to ask questions as I go,
哦，我应该提一下，随时随地提出问题，
um, totally fine to just,
嗯，完全没问题，
kind of, interact, uh, throughout.
有点，互动，呃，贯穿始终。
So here are some of the biases that I think are
所以这里有一些我认为的偏见
relatively important for work in AI and machine learning.
对人工智能和机器学习工作相对重要。
There's hundreds you can go into,
你可以进入数百种，
um, but some of the ones that I've, sort of,
嗯，但是有些我喜欢的，
become the most aware of working in this space,
成为最熟悉在这个领域工作的人，
um, are these sets and I'll go through each of these a bit.
嗯，这些是这些，我会仔细阅读这些内容。
Um, so I talked about reporting bias earlier,
嗯，所以我早些时候谈过报告偏见，
which is, uh, which affects what we can learn from text.
也就是说，这会影响我们从文本中学到什么。
Um, another example of a kind
嗯，另一个例子
of bias that really affects what we can learn from text is selection bias.
真正影响我们可以从文本中学到的东西的偏见是选择偏差。
So, uh, a lot of times that we,
所以，呃，我们很多次，
a lot of times when we get data annotated we'd use something
很多时候，当我们获得数据注释时，我们会使用一些东西
like Amazon's Mechanical Turk, um,
像亚马逊的机械土耳其人，嗯，
and the distribution of workers across the world is not even, sort of,
并且世界各地的工人分布都不均匀，
uniform distribution, it's actually, um,
均匀分布，实际上，嗯，
concentrated in India, the US and then some in Europe.
集中在印度，美国，然后一些在欧洲。
So this leaves out South America,
所以这留下了南美，
this leaves out Africa,
这离开了非洲，
this leaves out a lot of China and that affects the, kind of,
这留下了很多中国，这影响了，有点，
things that we'll be able to learn about the world when we have things annotated.
当我们注释事物时，我们将能够了解世界。
Um, another kind of bias is Out-group Homogeneity Bias,
嗯，另一种偏见是Out-group Homogeneity Bias，
which is the tendency to see out-group members as more alike than in-group members.
这种倾向会让群体成员看起来比群体内成员更相似。
And this is gonna affect what people are able to describe
这会影响人们能够描述的内容
and talk about when they're annotating things such as emotion.
并谈论他们何时注释情感等事物。
So, uh, so for example we have these two, like,
所以，呃，所以我们有这两个，比如，
adorable puppies on the left here and they're looking at these four cats.
左边的可爱的小狗，他们正在看这四只猫。
Um, these are all different black cats,
嗯，这些都是不同的黑猫，
very different in different ways,
在不同方面有很大不同，
but the two puppies look at the cats and they see four cats basically the same.
但两只小狗看着猫，他们看到四只猫基本相同。
And it's kind of trivial to understand how that also extends to
理解它是如何延伸到这一点也是微不足道的
human cognition and how we also process people.
人类的认知以及我们如何处理人。
Um, it's this- it's the sense we have that the,
嗯，就是这个 - 这是我们的意义，
the cohort that we're in,
我们所在的队列，
the people that we interact with,
我们互动的人，
those are the kinds of people that are nuanced and
那些是细微差别的人
everybody else is somehow less nuanced,
其他人在某种程度上不那么细微差别，
has less detail to them.
他们的细节较少。
It's a trick our minds play on us in order to help us process the world,
为了帮助我们处理世界，我们的思想在我们身上发挥作用，
but it affects how we talk about it and it affects further how we annotate it.
但它影响我们如何谈论它，它进一步影响我们如何注释它。
Um, this leads to stuff like biased data representations.
嗯，这导致了有偏见的数据表示之类的东西。
So it's possible that you have an appropriate amount of data for
因此，您可能拥有适当数量的数据
every possible human group you can think of in your data,
您可以在数据中考虑的每个可能的人类群体，
um, but it might be the case that some groups
嗯，但可能是某些团体的情况
are represented less positively than others.
表现得比其他人少。
And if we have time I'll go into, uh,
如果我们有时间，我会进去，呃，
a long- a longer example of that.
这是一个很长的例子。
Um, it also leads to things like biased labels.
嗯，它也会导致像有偏见的标签之类的东西。
So, um, this is an issue that came up when we were
所以，嗯，这是我们遇到的问题
getting some annotations for Inclusive Images competition,
获得包容性图像竞赛的一些注释，
asking people to annotate things like bride and wedding and groom.
要求人们注释诸如新娘，婚礼和新郎之类的东西。
And we found that given three different kinds of bride,
我们发现给了三种不同的新娘，
wedding and groom images,
婚礼和新郎图像，
um, ones that were more Western, European American, uh,
嗯，那些更西方的，欧洲的美国人，呃，
got the appropriate labels and ones that weren't,
得到了合适的标签和不合适的标签，
just got, sort of, more generic person,
刚才，有点，更通用的人，
kinds of, labels, uh,
种类，标签，呃，
not able to actually tease out what's actually happening in these images.
无法真正弄清楚这些图像中实际发生了什么。
Compounding this issue are biases in interpretation
使这个问题更加复杂的是解释上的偏见
when the model outputs, uh, its decisions.
当模型输出时，呃，它的决定。
So, um, one, one issue is confirmation bias,
所以，嗯，一个问题是确认偏见，
which is the tendency to search for, interpret, favor,
这是倾向于寻找，解释，支持，
recall information in a way that confirms preexisting beliefs.
以确认先前存在的信念的方式回忆信息。
And so a lot of times when we, uh,
很多时候我们，呃，
build end-to-end systems and try and test our hypotheses,
构建端到端系统并尝试测试我们的假设，
we're kind of just testing it towards, uh,
我们只是测试它，呃，
things that we want to be true and analyzing the results in a way that will,
我们想要成真的事情，并以一种方式分析结果，
uh, help confirm what we want to be true.
呃，帮助确认我们想要的是什么。
Um, overgeneralization, which is coming to
嗯，过度概括，即将到来
a conclusion based on information that's too general or not specific enough.
基于过于笼统或不够具体的信息得出的结论。
Um, this is an issue that happens a lot of times
嗯，这是一个很多次发生的问题
in the analysis of deep learning model results um,
在深度学习模型结果分析中，
where it's assumed that there's,
在哪里假设有，
there's some kind of general, uh,
有某种一般的，呃，
conclusion that can be taken away when really it's actually just,
结论可以带走，当它真的只是，
uh, an effect of really skewed data.
呃，真正扭曲数据的影响。
Um, this is also closely related to overfitting which
嗯，这也与过度拟合密切相关
is kind of the machine learning version of overgeneralization,
是一种过度概括的机器学习版本，
which is where you're still making predictions and outcomes,
这是你仍然在做预测和结果的地方，
but it's based on a small set of possible features, um,
但它基于一小部分可能的功能，嗯，
so it's not actually capturing the space of the correct features for the outcome,
所以它实际上并没有为结果捕获正确特征的空间，
uh, the desired output prediction correctly.
呃，正确的所需输出预测。
Um, there's also a correlation fallacy,
嗯，还有一个相关性谬误，
which is confusing correlation with causation.
这与因果关系混淆相关。
And this happens a lot again in talking about what
在谈论什么时，这又发生了很多
machine learning models are learning and
机器学习模型正在学习和
deep learning models are learning in particular, um,
深度学习模型正在特别学习，嗯，
where just because things happen together,
只是因为事情发生在一起，
doesn't mean that one is causing the other,
并不意味着一个人造成另一个，
but, uh, models don't tell you
但是，呃，模特不告诉你
anything- deep learning models directly don't
任何东西 - 深度学习模型都不直接
tell you anything about the causal relations.
告诉你关于因果关系的任何事情。
And so it's easy to think that some output that is predicted
因此很容易认为某些输出是预测的
based on a correlation is actually something that's causal,
基于相关性实际上是因果关系，
and I'll talk about some examples of this too.
我也会谈谈这方面的一些例子。
Um, a further issue is automation bias,
嗯，另一个问题是自动化偏差，
and this really affects the machine learning models we put out there in the world that
这真的影响了我们在世界上推出的机器学习模型
then get used by people in systems like justice systems.
然后被司法系统等系统中的人使用。
Um, so that's the tendency to, um,
嗯，这是倾向于，嗯，
favor the suggestions of
赞成的建议
automatic predictions of models that output predictions over the,
自动预测输出预测的模型，
um, uh, over the different kinds of um,
嗯，呃，对不同种类的嗯，
suggestions of another human.
另一个人的建议。
Um, and this happens even in the face of contradictory evidence.
嗯，即使面对相互矛盾的证据，也会发生这种情况。
So, if a system is telling you, you know, "This,
所以，如果系统告诉你，你知道，“这个，
this is the score or this is the risk of this individual",
这是分数，或者这是这个人的风险“，
then we're more likely to think it's true because it came out of a mathematical system,
然后我们更有可能认为它是真的，因为它来自一个数学系统，
and we automatically sort of see this as something more objective,
我们自动将这看作是更客观的东西，
something more mathematical, that something's going to
更具数学性的东西，即某种东西
be more true than humans some- somehow.
某种程度上比人类更真实。
Um, and that's automation bias.
嗯，这是自动化偏见。
So, um, rather than this kind of
所以，嗯，而不是这种
clean straightforward pipeline that we have in machine learning,
我们在机器学习中干净直接的管道，
um, we have human bias coming in at the very start in the data, um,
嗯，我们在数据的最开始就有人为的偏见，嗯，
and then human bias coming in in data collection, annotation,
然后人类偏见进入数据收集，注释，
and then further getting propagated through the system as we train on that data,
然后在我们训练数据时进一步传播通过系统，
um, as we start putting outputs based on that data,
嗯，当我们开始根据这些数据输出时，
as people act on that data.
当人们对这些数据采取行动时。
And this creates a feedback loop where
这会创建一个反馈循环
the kinds of things that we output for people to act on,
我们输出的各种事物，人们可以采取行动，
um, are then, are then,
嗯，那么，那么，
then serves as further training data for input into your system,
然后作为进一步的培训数据输入到您的系统，
so you end up amplifying even further these different kinds of implicit biases.
所以你最终会进一步扩大这些不同类型的隐含偏见。
This is known as a Bias Network Effect or Bias "Laundering", I like to call it.
这被称为偏置网络效应或偏见“洗涤”，我喜欢称之为。
And so, the message is that human data perpetuates human biases.
因此，信息是人类数据使人类的偏见永久化。
And then as as machine learning or deep learning learns from human data,
然后就像机器学习或深度学习从人类数据中学习一样，
the results is a bias network effect.
结果是偏见网络效应。
So, I want to steer clear of the idea that if I say bias or someone says bias that equals bad,
所以，我想避开这样的想法：如果我说偏见或有人说偏见等于坏，
it's a little bit more nuanced than that.
它比那更微妙。
Um, so there are all kinds of things that people
嗯，所以人们都有各种各样的东西
mean when they're talking about bias, um,
当他们谈论偏见时，这意味着，嗯，
and even the same bias can be good in some situations and bad in some situations,
甚至同样的偏见在某些情况下可能会很好，在某些情况下会很糟糕，
so bias in statistics and ML.
所以偏见统计和ML。
Um, we, we talk about the bias of an estimator which is
嗯，我们，我们谈论估计的偏见
the difference between the predictions and the truth, the ground truth.
预测和事实之间的区别，基本事实。
Uh, we talk about the bias term in linear regression.
呃，我们谈论线性回归中的偏差项。
Um, we also have cognitive biases,
嗯，我们也有认知偏见，
and I talked about that in the beginning,
我在开始时谈到了这一点，
and not all of those are negative or,
并非所有这些都是消极的，或
or have to be, uh,
或者必须是，呃，
or have to be seen as negative.
或者必须被视为消极的。
So optimism is another kind of bias that we can
所以乐观是我们能够做到的另一种偏见
have that affects our worldview and the way we sort of process things.
这会影响我们的世界观和我们处理事物的方式。
Um, and even things like recency bias and
嗯，甚至是新近偏见和
confirmation bias are just ways that our minds can like, um,
确认偏见是我们的思想可以喜欢的方式，嗯，
handle the combinatorial explosion of all the different things that can be
处理所有不同事物的组合爆炸
true in the world and put it down to something
在世界上是真实的，并把它归结为某种东西
tractable that we can sort of operate with in the real world.
我们可以在现实世界中进行操作。
Um, so algorithmic bias is what a lot
嗯，所以算法偏差是很多的
of people mean in headlines and whatnot when we're talking about bias,
当我们谈论偏见时，人们的意思是头条新闻
which is, uh, more about unjust,
这是，呃，更多关于不公正，
unfair or prejudicial treatment of people that's an output of,
对作为其产出的人的不公平或偏见的对待，
a automated decision system.
自动决策系统。
Um, and the focus here is really on, uh,
嗯，这里的重点是真的，呃，
unjust, unfair or prejudicial treatment of people.
对人不公正，不公平或有偏见的待遇。
So, a lot of the work in this space right now is focusing on trying to understand,
所以，现在这个领域的很多工作都集中在试图理解，
what does it mean to be unjust from an algorithm,
从算法中不公正是什么意思，
what does it mean to be unfair from an algorithm,
什么意思从算法不公平，
and how can we handle this,
我们该怎么办呢
how can we sort of mitigate these issues in order to be able to keep
我们怎样才能减轻这些问题，以便能够保持下去
developing technology that's useful for people without worsening social divides.
开发对人们有用而不会恶化社会分歧的技术。
Um, and I felt the Guardian put it really well a few years ago.
嗯，我觉得卫报几年前说得很好。
Um, they said, "Although neural networks might be said to write their own programs,
嗯，他们说，“虽然可以说神经网络可以编写自己的程序，
they do so towards goals set by humans using data collected for human purposes.
他们使用为人类目的收集的数据来实现人类设定的目标。
If the data is skewed, even by accident,
如果数据是倾斜的，即使是偶然的，
the computers will amplify injustice."
计算机将放大不公正。“
And it really keyed in on this amplify injustice idea.
它真正关键在于放大不公正的想法。
Um, and let's talk about what that can mean.
嗯，让我们来谈谈这意味着什么。
So, one of the avenues of deep learning research that's
因此，深度学习研究的途径之一就是
taken off in the past few years is predicting criminal behavior.
在过去几年中起飞是预测犯罪行为。
Um, so, um, how many of you are familiar with Predictive Policing?
嗯，那么，嗯，你们中有多少人熟悉预测性警务？
[NOISE] Okay, like, half of the class.
[NOISE]好的，就像，班级的一半。
Okay. So, in predictive policing, algorithms, um,
好的。所以，在预测性警务，算法，嗯，
predict areas to deploy officers where crime is considered to be likely to occur.
预测在可能发生犯罪的地方部署军官的区域。
But the data that the- the- the models are trained off
但是模型被训练的数据
of is based on where police officers have already gone and made arrests.
这取决于警察已经离开并逮捕的地方。
So, the systems are simply learning the patterns of bias that
因此，系统只是简单地学习偏见的模式
humans have and where do they go and where they are trying to decide to def- uh,
人类有，他们去哪里以及他们试图决定去哪里，
to find crime, um,
找到犯罪，嗯，
and then reflecting them back.
然后将它们反射回来。
So, because this system hones in on some of
所以，因为这个系统在某些方面闯入了
the top spots where people have been arrested,
人们被捕的最佳地点，
notice that's not the same of- that's
注意那不是那个 - 那个
the same thing as where crimes have been committed, right?
与犯罪的地方一样，对吧？
It's where arrests have been made.
这是逮捕的地方。
Um, it means that the other areas that
嗯，这意味着其他领域
might be explored for crime don't get explored at all.
可能被探索犯罪根本没有被探索。
That worsens the situation.
这使局势恶化。
Um, some neighborhoods, uh,
嗯，有些街区，呃，
get really acutely focused attention on them,
得到真正敏锐的关注他们，
and that heightens the chances of serious repercussions for
这增加了严重影响的可能性
even minor infractions, that means arrests.
即使是轻微的违规行为，也就是逮捕行为。
And that means a feedback loop of data that
这意味着数据的反馈循环
you will get an arrest in this place if you go there.
如果你去那里，你会在这个地方被捕。
Um, another, uh, sort of related issue in this space is, uh, predictive sentencing.
嗯，另一个，呃，这个领域的相关问题是，呃，预测量刑。
Um, so there was a really nice article that came out
嗯，所以有一篇非常好的文章出来了
from Pro- ProPublica a few years ago discussing this.
几年前Pro-ProPublica对此进行了讨论。
Um, but when most defendants are booked in jail,
嗯，但当大多数被告在监狱里被预定时，
they respond to a questionnaire called COMPAS.
他们回复了一份名为COMPAS的调查问卷。
Um, and their answers are fed into this software system that
嗯，他们的答案被输入到这个软件系统中
generates scores that correspond to the risk of recidivism,
产生与累犯风险相对应的分数，
that's the risk of um,
这是嗯的风险，
er, making a crime again.
呃，又犯了罪。
Um, and the questions are used to gather data
嗯，这些问题用于收集数据
on the defendant's socio-economic status,
关于被告的社会经济地位，
family background, neighborhood crime,
家庭背景，邻里犯罪，
employment status, and other factors in order to reach
就业状况，以及其他因素，以达到
some predictim- prediction of an individual's crime or criminal risk.
对个人犯罪或犯罪风险的预测。
Um, but what ends up happening is that it ends up focusing on the key bias issues
嗯，但最终发生的事情是它最终关注的是关键的偏见问题
that humans have and propagating it
人类拥有并传播它
back with something that looks like an objective score.
回来的东西看起来像客观分数。
So, you're a lot more likely um,
所以，你更有可能，嗯，
to be convicted of a crime, um,
被定罪的嗯，嗯，
if you're black than if you're white,
如果你是黑人而不是你是白人，
even if you've made the exact same crime.
即使你犯了同样的罪行。
And the system will pick up on this,
系统会接受这个，
and will reflect this back to say that people who are
并会反映这一点，说是那些人
black are more likely to have reci- like recidivism,
黑人更有可能重新接受累犯，
more likely to convict a,
更有可能定罪，
uh, to make a crime again.
呃，再犯一次罪。
Um, so this is an example of automation bias, preferring the output of a system, uh,
嗯，所以这是自动化偏差的一个例子，更喜欢系统的输出，呃，
in the face of overgeneralization, feedback loops,
面对过度概括，反馈循环，
and correlation fallacy,
和相关性谬误，
confusing things that are occurring together as being somehow causal.
令人困惑的事情在一起发生，因为某种程度上是因果关系。
There's another, uh, sort of area of research and, uh,
还有另一种呃，研究领域，呃，
startups looking at predicting criminality in particular from things like face images.
初创公司正在研究预测犯罪行为，尤其是面部图像等。
So there's a company out there, uh, called Faception.
所以那里有一家公司，呃，名为Faception。
They are based in Israel and they claim to be able to,
他们的总部设在以色列，他们声称能够，
um, use individual images, uh,
嗯，使用个人形象，呃，
with computer vision and machine learning technology for profiling people
用计算机视觉和机器学习技术来描绘人
and revealing their personality based only on their facial image,
并仅根据他们的面部形象揭示他们的个性，
um, recognizing things like high IQ,
嗯，认识到高智商，
white-collar offender, pedophile, and terrorist.
白领罪犯，恋童癖者和恐怖分子。
Um, and their main clients are Homeland Security,
嗯，他们的主要客户是国土安全部，
lots of other, uh,
很多其他的，呃，
lots of other countries dealing with sort of public safety issues.
处理各种公共安全问题的许多其他国家。
They've not published any details about their methods,
他们没有公布任何关于他们方法的细节，
their sources of training data,
他们的培训数据来源，
or their quantitative results.
或他们的定量结果。
We know that in light of automation bias,
我们知道，鉴于自动化偏见，
people will tend to think it just works even when it doesn't work well.
人们会倾向于认为它只是在它不能正常工作时才有效。
Um, but there was a paper that came out wi- in
嗯，但有一篇文章出现了
a similar line predicting criminal, criminality,
类似的预测犯罪，犯罪，
or purporting to predict criminality from individual face images,
或旨在预测个人脸部图像的犯罪行为，
and that one had some results and,
那个人有一些结果，
uh, some more details about the data that we could kinda dig
呃，关于我们可以挖掘的数据的更多细节
into to understand where are these kinds of claims coming from.
了解这些类型的索赔来自何处。
Um, so this was an article that was posted on Archive near the end of 2016.
嗯，所以这篇文章于2016年底发布在Archive上。
Um, and they said they were using less than 2,000 closely cropped images of faces, um,
嗯，他们说他们使用了不到2000张紧密裁剪的面孔图像，嗯，
including wanted suspect ID pictures from specific regions,
包括来自特定地区的想要的可疑身份证照片，
and they claimed that even based on this very small training dataset, um,
他们声称即使是基于这个非常小的训练数据集，嗯，
that they were able to predict, uh,
他们能够预测，呃，
whether or not someone was likely to be a criminal,
是否有人可能是罪犯，
uh, greater than 90 percent accuracy.
呃，准确率超过90％。
Um, and they got so lost in this,
嗯，他们在这里迷路了，
this idea that, uh,
这个想法，呃，
it's sort of funny to read to just take
读起来很有趣
a step back and realize what's actually happening.
退后一步，意识到实际发生了什么。
So for example, one of
例如，其中之一
their really great exciting claims was that the angle Theta from nose tip to
他们真正令人兴奋的主张是从鼻尖到角尖的角度Theta
two mouth corners is on average
两个嘴角平均
19,6 percent smaller for criminals than for non-criminals.
犯罪分子比非犯罪分子少19,6％。
This is otherwise known as smiling. [LAUGHTER]
这被称为微笑。 [笑声]
Uh, and [LAUGHTER] you know,
呃，[大笑]你知道吗，
exactly the kind of images people would
正是人们想要的那种形象
use when trying to put out wanted criminal pictures,
在试图推出想要的犯罪照片时使用
probably not really happy pictures.
可能不是很开心的照片。
But you get so lost in the confirmation bias.
但你在确认偏见中迷失了方向。
You get so lost in the correlation and the
你在相关性和迷失中迷失了
feedback loops that you end up overlooking these
反馈循环，你最终忽略了这些
really obvious kinds of things.
真的很明显的东西。
Um, so that's an example of selection bias,
嗯，这是选择偏差的一个例子，
experimenter's bias, confirmation bias, correlation fallacy,
实验者的偏见，确认偏差，相关性谬误，
and feedback loops all coming together to create
和反馈循环一起创建
a deep learning system that people think is
一个人们认为的深度学习系统
scary and can do things that it can't actually do.
可怕而且可以做一些它实际上无法做到的事情。
Um, one of the issues with this was that the media loved it.
嗯，其中一个问题是媒体喜欢它。
Like it was all over the news,
喜欢这个全新闻，
and there's been similar kinds of things happening again and again.
并且一直有类似的事情一次又一次地发生。
Media wants to sell the story,
媒体想要出售这个故事，
and so it's part of our job as researchers,
所以这是我们作为研究人员的工作的一部分，
that people who work on this stuff,
从事这项工作的人，
to be very clear about what the technology is actually doing,
要非常清楚技术实际在做什么，
uh, and make a distinction between what you
呃，并区分你
might think it's doing and what it's actually doing.
可能会认为它正在做，它实际上在做什么。
Um, so another issue that has come up recently, um,
嗯，最近又出现了另一个问题，嗯，
it's claiming to be able to predict
它声称能够预测
internal qualities but specifically ones that are subject to discrimination,
内部品质，但特别是受歧视的品质，
um, and loss of opportunity.
嗯，失去机会。
So in particular, there was this work that came out that claimed
所以特别是，声称有这项工作
to be able to predict whether or not someone was homosexual,
能够预测某人是否是同性恋，
just based on single face images.
只是基于单面图像。
Um, now, it's important to know that the images that they used in the study included
嗯，现在，知道他们在研究中使用的图像包括在内是很重要的
images that were from dating websites where people self-identified as straight or gay,
来自约会网站的图片，人们自认为是直接或同性恋，
and identified as whether they were looking for a partner who was straight or gay,
并确定他们是在寻找直接或同性恋的伴侣，
and these became the sources of the training data,
这些成为培训数据的来源，
and still from this, uh.
还是从这个，呃。
Oh! Before I go on, can you guys just understand
哦!在我继续之前，你们可以理解
just from that what the issue might have been?
只是从那个问题可能是什么？
Rainbows.
彩虹。
[LAUGHTER] I don't think that there was actually anything about rainbows,
[笑声]我认为实际上并没有关于彩虹的事情，
but that's really unfortunate.
但这真的很不幸。
[LAUGHTER].
[笑声]。
[inaudible]
[听不见]
Right. Yeah. So this has more to do with the presentation of the self,
对。是啊。所以这更多地与自我的呈现有关，
the presentation of the social self when you're trying to for example,
例如，当您尝试时，社交自我的呈现，
attract a partner on a website,
吸引网站上的合作伙伴，
and less to do with how you look day to day.
而且与你日常生活的方式关系不大。
Um, and yet they kind of went to
嗯，但他们有点过去了
these large conclusions that aren't supported at all by the data or by their study,
这些大的结论完全没有得到数据或他们的研究的支持，
um, but things like consistent with a prenatal hormone theory of sexual orientation.
嗯，但事情就像产前激素性取向理论一致。
Gay men and women tended to have gender atypical facial morphology.
同性恋男性和女性往往具有性别非典型的面部形态。
Now, none of the authors actually were prenatal hormone theory specialists, you know.
现在，没有一个作者真的是产前激素理论专家，你知道。
They have doctor in their name so maybe that's a thing.
他们的名字中有医生，所以也许这就是事情。
Um, this was a Stanford professor and like I've,
嗯，这是斯坦福大学教授，就像我一样，
I've presented this a few times at Stanford and gotten into
我在斯坦福大学曾多次介绍过这本书
some like pretty harsh fights about this.
有些人喜欢非常严厉的打架。
So I'm ready if anyone wants to take me on.
所以如果有人想带我，我准备好了。
[LAUGHTER] But uh, me and my uh,
[大笑]但是，呃，我和我，呃，
some of my colleagues decided we'd,
我的一些同事决定我们，
we'd play around with this a bit,
我们会玩这个，
and what we found was that a simple decision tree.
我们发现的是一个简单的决策树。
Um, so I'm kind of assuming you guys know what a decision tree is.
嗯，所以我假设你们知道决策树是什么。
So, okay.
好吧，好吧。
Cool. So based on wearing makeup or wearing glasses,
凉。所以基于化妆或戴眼镜，
got us pretty close to the accuracy reported in
让我们非常接近报告的准确性
the paper. That says nothing about internal hormones,
论文。这对内部激素没有任何意义，
that says nothing about any of that,
什么都没说
and it says a lot about the physical presentation,
它说了很多关于物理演示的内容，
the things that are on the surface.
表面上的东西。
Um, it says a lot more about how people are
嗯，它更多地讲述了人们的情况
presenting themselves than what is happening internally.
展示自己而不是内部发生的事情。
Um, so the key thing that's recently kind of
嗯，这是最近的关键
been overlooked is that deep learning is somehow,
被忽视的是深度学习是某种方式，
i- it's sort of considered that it's somehow magically going beyond surface level.
我认为它在某种程度上神奇地超越了表面层面。
But the point is that it's working on the surface level and working well.
但关键是它在表面层面上工作并且运行良好。
And in the face of confirmation bias and other kinds of bias factors,
面对确认偏见和其他种类的偏见因素，
it's easy to assume that something else is happening that's not.
很容易假设其他事情正在发生，但事实并非如此。
Without critical examination, uh,
没有批判性的检查，呃，
for example simple baselines, uh,
例如简单的基线，呃，
simple sanity checks, these kinds of things can just be ignored and,
简单的理智检查，这些事情可以忽略不计，
and not noticed at all.
并没有注意到。
Um, so that's example of selection bias,
嗯，这是选择偏差的例子，
um, experimenter's bias, and correlation fallacy.
嗯，实验者的偏见和相关性谬误。
Okay. So now I'm going to talk to,
好的。所以现在我要和他说话，
talk about measuring algorithmic bias.
谈论测量算法偏差。
So I just said a lot about different kinds of biases that come in in the data,
所以我只是说了很多关于数据中出现的各种偏见，
in the collection, in the interpretation of the results.
在集合中，在结果的解释中。
[NOISE] Let's talk about actually quantitatively measuring different kinds of biases.
[NOISE]让我们谈谈实际上定量测量不同类型的偏差。
Um, so one of the key things that's, uh,
嗯，所以关键的事情之一，呃，
emerged in a few different works and really ties nicely to a lot
出现在一些不同的作品中，真的很好地联系了很多
of fairness work is this idea of disaggregated evaluation.
公平工作是这种分解评价的想法。
So in disaggregated evaluation,
所以在分类评估中，
you evaluate across different subgroups as opposed to
你评估不同的子群而不是
looking at one single score for your overall testing data set.
查看整个测试数据集的单个分数。
Um, so, okay.
嗯，好吧。
You guys are probably familiar with the training testing data split.
你们可能熟悉训练测试数据分割。
You kind of train on there,
你在那里训练，
on your given training data,
根据您提供的培训数据，
you test on your given testing data and then you repo- you report like precision,
你测试你给定的测试数据，然后你回复报告像精度，
recall, F-score, things like that.
回忆，F-score，这样的事情。
Um, but what that masks is how well the system is actually
嗯，但是掩盖的是系统实际上的表现
working across different kinds of individuals and across different, different subgroups.
在不同类型的个人和不同的不同子群体中工作。
Um, and so one just straightforward way to handle
嗯，所以一个只是直截了当的处理方式
this is to actually evaluate with respect to those different subgroups.
这是为了对这些不同的子群进行实际评估。
So creating for each sort of subgroup prediction pair.
因此，为每种子组预测对创建。
Um, so for an example,
嗯，举个例子，
you might look at women face detection,
你可能会看一下女性面部检测，
men face detection, and look at how the,
男人面对检测，看看怎么样，
the error rates are,
错误率是，
are different or are um, similar.
是不同的或是嗯，相似。
Um, another important part of this is to look at things intersectionally,
嗯，另一个重要的部分是交叉地看待事物，
um, combining things, um,
嗯，把事情结合起来，嗯，
like gender and race at the same time and seeing how those, uh,
喜欢性别和种族同时看到那些，呃，
how the error rates on those sorts of things
这些事情的错误率如何
change and how they're different across uh, different intersections.
变化以及它们在不同的交叉点之间的差异。
Um, and this is inspired by Kimberle Crenshaw.
嗯，这是受到Kimberle Crenshaw的启发。
Um, who she, she pioneered intersectional research,
嗯，她，她开创了交叉研究，
uh, in critical race theory.
呃，在批判种族理论中。
Um, and she discussed the story of Emma DeGraffenreid, uh,
嗯，她讨论了Emma DeGraffenreid的故事，呃，
who was a woman at General Motors, um,
谁是通用汽车的女人，嗯，
and she claimed that the company's hiring practices discriminated against black women.
她声称该公司的招聘做法歧视黑人妇女。
Um, but in her court opinion,
嗯，但在她的法庭意见中，
the judges ruled that General Motors hired, um,
法官裁定通用汽车聘请，嗯，
many women for secretarial positions and many black people for factory roles,
许多妇女担任秘书职位，许多黑人担任工厂职务，
and thus they could not have discriminated against black women.
因此他们不能歧视黑人妇女。
What they failed to do was look at the intersection of
他们没有做的是看看交叉点
the two and understand that the experience there might be
两者并了解可能存在的经验
fundamentally different than any of
从根本上不同于任何一个
the experiences of either of these sort of subgroups in isolation.
这些子群中任何一个的经验都是孤立的。
Um, and the same becomes true when you start looking
嗯，当你开始寻找时也是如此
at errors that are regularly made in deep learning systems.
在深度学习系统中经常出现的错误。
Um, so we've been able to uncover a lot of
嗯，所以我们已经能够发现很多
different kinds of unintended errors by looking not only at
不仅仅是在寻找不同类型的意外错误
the disaggregated evaluation but also at intersectional disaggregated evaluation.
分类评估，但也在交叉分解评估。
Um, so I'm going to walk through a bit how this works.
嗯，所以我将详细介绍一下这是如何工作的。
This is probably going to be review for most of you,
这可能是大多数人的评论，
but I think it's really important to understand this because it also
但我认为理解这一点非常重要，因为它也是如此
ties to how we measure fairness and when we say like,
与我们衡量公平的方式有关，当我们说出来时，
uh, algorithmic fairness, what we're talking about.
呃，算法公平，我们在谈论什么。
So um, the confusion matrix is a way, you guys.
嗯，混淆矩阵是一种方式，你们。
Okay. Are you guys familiar with the confusion matrix?
好的。你们熟悉混淆矩阵吗？
[LAUGHTER]. I just want want to know where.
[笑声]。我只是想知道在哪里。
Okay. Awesome. Cool. So you're familiar with the confusion matrix, right.
好的。真棒。凉。所以你对混淆矩阵很熟悉吧。
So you have model predictions and references.
所以你有模型预测和参考。
Um, and you can kind of look at these as negative and positive,
嗯，你可以把这些视为消极和积极的，
uh, binary classification, uh,
呃，二元分类，呃，
kind of approach here where if
这种方法在哪里如果
the ground truth says something is true and the model predicts it's true,
事实说明事情是真的，模型预测它是真的，
it's a true positive.
这是一个真正的积极因素。
If the ground truth says, uh,
如果说实话，呃，
it's, it's, it's false,
它是，它是，它是假的，
um, and the model predicts it's false, it's true negative.
嗯，模型预测它是假的，这是真的消极。
Um, and the errors that the kind of different issues that
嗯，那种错误就是那种不同的问题
arise are false negatives and false positives.
出现的是假阴性和误报。
Um, so in false positives the, um,
嗯，所以在误报中，嗯，
the ground truth says something is negative but the model predicts that it's positive.
事实证明某些事情是消极的，但该模型预测它是积极的。
Uh, and then in false negatives, vice versa.
呃，然后是假阴性，反之亦然。
Um, from these, you know,
嗯，从这些，你知道，
uh, basic kind of, uh,
呃，基本的，呃，
these basic breakdown of errors,
这些错误的基本细分，
you can get a few different metrics.
你可以得到一些不同的指标。
Um, these metrics actually trivially map to a lot of different fairness criteria.
嗯，这些指标实际上很容易映射到很多不同的公平标准。
So um, for example,
所以，嗯，例如，
if we're looking at something like
如果我们正在寻找类似的东西
a female versus male patient results and figuring out things like precision and recall,
女性与男性患者的结果，并找出精确和召回等事情，
which is relatively common in NLP, um,
这在NLP中比较常见，嗯，
if you have equal recall across your subgroups
如果你的子组中有相同的召回率
that's the same as the fairness criteria of equality of opportunity,
这与机会均等的公平标准相同，
um, I could work through the math.
嗯，我可以通过数学计算。
But I mean, this is basically just,
但我的意思是，这基本上就是，
just the main point that, that, uh,
只是主要的一点，呃，
it says that given that something is true in the ground truth,
它说，鉴于事实真相，
the model should predict that it's true,
模型应该预测它是真的，
uh, at equal rates across different subgroups.
呃，不同小组的费率相同。
So this ends up being equivalent to having the same recall across different subgroups.
因此，这最终相当于在不同的子组中进行相同的召回。
Similarly, um, having the same precision across
同样，嗯，具有相同的精度
different subgroups is equivalent to a fairness criterion called predictive parity.
不同的子群等同于称为预测奇偶性的公平性标准。
And so as fairness has been defined again and again, um,
因此，公平性一再被定义，嗯，
it was originally some of these definitions came in
它最初是其中一些定义的来源
1966 following the Civil Rights Act of 1964.
1966年遵循1964年民权法案。
Um, they were reinvented a few times, uh,
嗯，他们被重新发明了几次，呃，
and most recently reinvented in, uh, 2016.
并且最近在2016年重新发明了。
Um, but they all sort of boiled down to
嗯，但他们都有点归结为
this disaggregated comparison across subgroups and the math,
这是分组和数学的分类比较，
the metrics end being roughly equivalent to what we get from the confusion matrix,
度量结束大致相当于我们从混淆矩阵得到的，
specifically in classification systems.
特别是在分类系统中。
So which kind of fairness metric do you use,
那么你使用哪种公平度量，
what are the different criteria you want
你想要的标准是什么？
to use to look at the differences across different subgroups,
用来看看不同子群体之间的差异，
that really comes down to the trade-offs
这真的归结为权衡
between false positives and false negatives.
假阳性和假阴性之间。
So this is the same problem that you are dealing with
所以这与您正在处理的问题相同
when you're just figuring out how to evaluate generally.
当你只想弄清楚如何评估时。
Um, there's no one fairness criteria and that is
嗯，没有一个公平标准，那就是
the fairness criteria and to rule them all, um,
公平标准，并统治他们所有，嗯，
deciding which one is better than the other is the same as
决定哪一个优于另一个是相同的
kind of trying to decide which is better, precision or recall, right?
有点试图决定哪个更好，更准确或召回，对吧？
It depends on what the problem is and what you're interested in measuring.
这取决于问题是什么以及您对测量感兴趣。
Um, so a case where false positives might be better than
嗯，假阳性可能比好的情况好
false negatives and so you want to prioritize something like a false positive rate,
假阴性，所以你想优先考虑假阳性率，
ah, across subgroups is privacy and images.
啊，跨子组是隐私和图像。
So here a false positive is something that doesn't need to be blurred gets blurred.
所以这里的假阳性是不需要模糊的东西变得模糊。
That's just kind of a bummer.
那只是一种无赖。
Um, but a false negative would be something that needs to be
嗯，但是假阴性将是需要的东西
blurred is not blurred and that can be identity theft.
模糊不模糊，可以是身份盗窃。
It's a much more serious issue.
这是一个更严重的问题。
And so it's important to prioritize
因此优先考虑是非常重要的
the evaluation metrics that stress the false negative rates.
强调假阴性率的评估指标。
Um, an example where false negatives
嗯，假阴性的例子
might be better than false positives is in spam filtering.
垃圾邮件过滤可能比误报更好。
So a false-negative could be an e-mail that's spam not caught so you see it in your inbox,
因此，假阴性可能是一封垃圾邮件未被捕获的电子邮件，因此您可以在收件箱中看到它，
that's usually just annoying, it's not a big deal.
这通常很烦人，这不是什么大不了的事。
Um, but a false positive here would be e-mail flagged as
嗯，但这里的误报将被标记为电子邮件
spam and then removed from your inbox, which,
垃圾邮件然后从您的收件箱中删除，
you know, if its from a friend or a loved one,
你知道，如果它来自朋友或亲人，
it can be, it can be a loss,
它可以，它可能是一种损失，
maybe a job offer something like that.
也许一份工作提供类似的东西。
All right.
行。
So, um, I just kind of covered how AI can unintentionally lead to
所以，嗯，我只是介绍了AI如何无意中导致的问题
unjust outcomes and some of the things to do
不公正的结果和一些要做的事情
or some of the things to be aware of here,
或者这里要注意的一些事情，
are the lack of insight into sources of bias in the data, in the model,
在模型中，缺乏对数据偏差来源的洞察力，
lack of insight into the feedback loops from the original data that's collected
缺乏对收集的原始数据的反馈循环的深入了解
as an example of what humans do to the data that's then repurposed,
作为人类对随后改变用途的数据所做的事情的一个例子，
re-used, acted on, and then further fed in.
重复使用，行动，然后进一步喂养。
Um, a lack of careful disaggregated evaluation,
嗯，缺乏仔细的分类评估，
looking at the disparities,
看着差距，
the differences between different subgroups in order to understand this bias,
不同亚组之间的差异，以了解这种偏见，
this difference across the subgroups.
这种差异在各个小组之间。
Um, and then human biases in interpreting, and accepting,
嗯，然后人类在解释和接受时的偏见，
and talking about the results,
并谈论结果，
which then kind of further the media cycles and the hype around AI right now.
然后进一步的媒体循环和围绕AI的炒作现在。
Um, but it's up to us to influence how AI evolves.
嗯，但是我们应该影响人工智能的演变。
So I like to think of this in terms of short term,
所以我想从短期来看这个，
middle term, and long-term objectives.
中期和长期目标。
So short term today,
如此短暂的今天，
we might be working on some specific model where we're trying to find some local optimum,
我们可能正在研究一些特定的模型，我们试图找到一些局部最优，
we have a task, we have data, something like that.
我们有一个任务，我们有数据，类似的东西。
And that's sort of short-term objectives.
这就是短期目标。
Um, we might have a slightly longer-term objective of getting a paper published,
嗯，我们可能会有一个稍微长期的目标来发表一篇论文，
or if you're an industry like getting a product launched,
或者如果你是一个像推出产品这样的行业，
whatever it might be.
无论它是什么。
Um, from there we might see our next endpoint is getting an award or,
嗯，从那里我们可能会看到我们的下一个终点是获得奖励，或者
you know, maybe become sort of famous for something for
你知道，也许会成为一些着名的东西
a few minutes, something like that and that's cool.
几分钟，类似的东西，这很酷。
Um, but there's a longer-term objective that we
嗯，但我们有一个长期目标
can work towards as well at the same time.
也可以同时努力。
And that's something like a positive outcome for humans in their environment.
这就像人类在环境中的积极结果。
So instead of just kind of focusing on these local decisions,
因此，不要只关注这些本地决策，
these local optima and these
这些局部最优和这些
sort of local paper by paper-based approaches to solving problems,
通过基于纸张的方法来解决问题，
you can also kind of think about what's the long-term objective.
你也可以考虑什么是长期目标。
Where does this get me as I trace out an evolutionary path for artificial intelligence,
当我找到人工智能的进化路径时，这会让我感到满意，
down the line in 10 years,
在10年内下线，
15 years, 20 years.
15年，20年。
Um, and one of the ways you can address this is by thinking,
嗯，你可以解决这个问题的方法之一就是思考，
now how can the work I'm interested in now be best focused to help others?
现在，我现在感兴趣的工作如何才能最好地专注于帮助他人？
And that involves talking to experts,
这涉及与专家交谈，
um, and kind of going outside your bubble,
嗯，有点走出你的泡沫，
speaking across interdisciplinary fields like
跨越跨学科领域，如
cognitive science which I've just talked a bit about.
我刚才谈到的认知科学。
Um, so let's talk about some things we can do.
嗯，让我们谈谈我们可以做的一些事情。
So first off is data.
首先是数据。
Um, so a lot of the issues of bias and fairness,
嗯，所以有很多偏见和公平的问题，
ah, in machine learning models really come down to the data.
啊，在机器学习模型中真的归结为数据。
Unfortunately in machine learning and deep learning,
不幸的是机器学习和深度学习，
working on data is really not seen as sexy.
处理数据真的不像性感。
Ah, there's a few datasets, ah,
啊，有几个数据集，啊，
that people use that are out there,
人们使用那里，
that's what people use,
那就是人们用的东西，
and there's not a lot of analysis done on,
而且没有做过很多分析，
on how well these datasets capture different truths about the world,
这些数据集如何捕获有关世界的不同真理，
how problematic they might be,
他们可能有多大问题，
[NOISE] um, but it's a pretty wide area that needs a lot of future,
[NOISE]嗯，但这是一个非常广阔的领域，需要很多未来，
like lea- needs a lot of future additional work.
像lea需要很多未来的额外工作。
Um, [NOISE] so we're going to understanding the data skews and the correlations.
嗯，[NOISE]所以我们要了解数据偏差和相关性。
If you understand your data skews and the,
如果你了解你的数据偏差和，
ah, correlations that might be problematic in your data,
啊，你的数据可能有问题的相关性，
then you can start working on either models that address those,
然后你可以开始处理那些解决这些问题的模型，
or data augmentation approaches in order to sort of make
或数据增加方法，以便进行排序
the dataset a little bit better or a little bit more representative
数据集更好一点或更具代表性
of how you want the world to be.
你想要世界的方式。
Um, it's also important to abandon the single training set- testing
嗯，放弃单一训练集测试也很重要
set from similar distribution approach to advancing deep learning.
从类似的分配方法来推进深度学习。
So um, when we do projects in deep learning,
那么，当我们进行深度学习项目时，
you know, we tend to have the training set,
你知道，我们倾向于有训练集，
and the testing set and then that's what we sort of benchmark on and prioritize,
和测试集，然后这就是我们的基准和优先级，
but the point is, as you move around different testing sets,
但关键是，当您在不同的测试集周围移动时，
you're gonna get vastly different results.
你会得到截然不同的结果。
Um, and so by keeping in
嗯，等等
this just sort of one training testing dat- training testing dataset paradigm,
这只是一种训练测试数据训练测试数据集范例，
you're really likely to not notice issues that might otherwise be there.
你真的可能不会注意到可能存在的问题。
And one way to really focus in on them,
还有一种真正专注于它们的方法，
is having a hard set of,
有一套硬盘，
of test cases, that you really wanna make sure the model does well on.
测试用例，你真的想确保模型做得好。
So these are things that are particularly problematic.
所以这些都是特别成问题的。
Things that would be really harmful to individuals,
对个人有害的事情，
um, If they were to experience the output.
嗯，如果他们要体验输出。
Um, and you kinda collect those in a small test set and then it's really easy
嗯，你有点收集那些小测试集，然后它真的很容易
to evaluate on that test set as you benchmark improvements on your model,
在您对模型进行基准测试时评估该测试集，
as you add different kinds of things to your model,
当你为模型添加不同类型的东西时，
in order to see, um,
为了看，嗯，
not just how your model is doing overall,
不仅仅是你的模型如何做到整体，
in terms of your testing dataset,
就您的测试数据集而言，
but how well you're doing in terms of these examples,
但是你在这些例子方面的表现如何，
you really want it to do well on.
你真的希望它做得好。
That you know that is going to be a problem if it doesn't do well on,
你知道如果它不能很好地成为一个问题，
and any sort of degradation in that,
以及任何类型的退化，
you might want to prioritize, um,
你可能想要优先考虑，嗯，
to fix above degragaish- degradation and overall accuracy.
修复以上降解 - 降解和整体准确性。
Um, and it's also important to talk to experts
嗯，和专家交谈也很重要
about the additional signals that you can incorporate.
关于您可以合并的其他信号。
Um, so we've put out a tool to help with this,
嗯，所以我们推出了一个工具来帮助解决这个问题，
ah, understanding data skews called facets,
嗯，理解称为facets的数据偏差，
um, it's just available there.
嗯，它只在那里可用。
Um, and it's a really handy kinda visualizer for slicing, ah, understanding,
嗯，它是一个非常方便的切片可视化器啊，理解，
um, you know, what some of the differences are between different subgroups
嗯，你知道，不同子组之间存在一些差异
and different representations and you can sort of dig in and explore a bit more.
和不同的表示，你可以挖掘和探索更多。
So this is just to sort of help people, ah,
所以这只是为了帮助人啊，
come to terms with the data that they're actually using and,
与他们实际使用的数据达成协议，
and where there might be, um,
那里可能有，嗯，
unwanted associations or, or missing,
不想要的关联或缺失，
missing kind of features.
缺少一些功能。
[NOISE] Um, another approach that's been put forward recently,
[NOISE]嗯，这是最近提出的另一种方法，
ah, specifically on the data side is this data,
啊，具体在数据方面是这个数据，
datasheets for datasets approach.
数据集方法的数据表。
Um, so this is this idea that when you release a dataset,
嗯，所以这个想法是当你发布一个数据集时，
it's not enough to just release the dataset with like
仅仅发布数据集是不够的
some pretty graphs and like talking about basic distributional information,
一些漂亮的图表，比如谈论基本的分布信息，
you need to talk about who the annotators were, where they were,
你需要谈谈注释者是谁，他们在哪里，
what the inter-annotator agreement was,
注释器间协议是什么，
what their background information was,
他们的背景信息是什么，
um, motivation for the dataset.
嗯，数据集的动机。
All these other kinds of details.
所有这些其他类型的细节。
So now you actually know that this isn't just a dataset,
所以现在你实际上知道这不仅仅是一个数据集，
this is a dataset that has these specific biases.
这是一个具有这些特定偏差的数据集。
There's no such thing as a dataset that isn't biased in some way.
没有数据集不会以某种方式存在偏差。
A dataset by virtue of the fact that it's collected from the world as a subset,
一个数据集，因为它是从世界收集的一个子集，
is a, is a biased set of the world in some way.
是一个，在某种程度上是一个有偏见的世界。
The point is to make it clear what it is,
关键是要清楚它是什么，
how it is biased, what are the,
它是如何有偏见的，是什么，
what are the various biases,
什么是各种偏见，
ah, that are important to know about in the dataset.
啊，在数据集中了解很重要。
So that's one of these ideas between- behind datasheets for datasets,
这就是数据集数据表之间的这些想法之一，
releasing its datasets publicly.
公开发布其数据集。
All right. Now let's switch a little bit to machine learning.
行。现在让我们切换一下机器学习。
Um, so there are a couple of techniques that I like to use. Um, I'll talk about two.
嗯，所以我喜欢使用几种技术。嗯，我会谈两个。
One, ah, is bias mitigation,
一个啊，是偏见缓解，
which is removing the signal for a problematic output.
这是为有问题的输出删除信号。
Um, so removing, ah, stereotyping,
嗯，所以删除，啊，刻板印象，
sexism, racism, trying to remove these kind of effects from the model.
性别歧视，种族主义，试图从模型中消除这些影响。
Um, this is also sometimes called de-biasing or unbiasing,
嗯，这有时也被称为去偏置或不偏不倚，
but that's a little bit of a misnomer because you're- you're generally just kind of
但这有点用词不当，因为你 - 你通常只是一种
moving around bias based on a specific set of words for example,
例如，根据一组特定的单词移动偏见
um, so to say it's unbiased is is not true.
嗯，所以说它没有偏见是不正确的。
Um, but you are kind of mitigating bias with respect to
嗯，但你有点减轻偏见
some certain kinds of information that you provide it with.
您提供的某些特定信息。
Um, and there's inclusion which is then adding signal for desired variables.
嗯，然后包含然后为所需变量添加信号。
So that's kind of the opposite side of bias mitigation.
这就是偏见缓解的另一面。
So increasing model performance with attention to
因此，注意增加模型性能
subgroups or data slices with the worst performance.
性能最差的子组或数据切片。
Um, so, ah, in order to,
嗯，啊，为了，
er, address inclusion, ah,
呃，地址包含啊，
kind of adding signal for under-represented sub-groups,
为代表性不足的子群添加信号，
one technique that's worked relatively well is multi-task learning.
一种工作相对较好的技术是多任务学习。
Um, so I've heard that you guys have studied multi-task learning which is great,
嗯，所以我听说你们学过多任务学习很棒，
um, so I'll tell you a bit about a case study here.
嗯，所以我会在这里告诉你一个案例研究。
Um, so this is work I did, ah,
嗯，这是我做的工作啊，
in collaboration with a UPenn World Well-being Project, ah,
与UPenn世界福祉项目合作啊，
working directly with clinicians,
直接与临床医生合作，
and the goal was to create a system that could alert
目标是创建一个可以提醒的系统
clinicians if there was a suicide attempt that was imminent.
临床医生是否有即将发生的自杀企图。
Um, and they wanted to understand the feasibility of
嗯，他们想了解的可行性
these kinds of diagnoses when there were very few training,
当训练很少时，这些诊断，
ah, training instances available.
啊，训练实例可用。
So that's similar to kind of the minority problem in datasets.
这类似于数据集中的少数问题。
Um, [NOISE]
嗯，[NOISE]
And, uh, in this work,
而且，呃，在这项工作中，
we had two kinds of data.
我们有两种数据。
One was the internal data which was the electronic health records, um,
一个是内部数据，即电子健康记录，嗯，
with the- that was either provided by the patient or from the family.
与 - 由患者或家人提供。
Um, it included mental health diagnoses,
嗯，它包括心理健康诊断，
uh, suicide attempts or completions, um,
呃，自杀未遂或完成，嗯，
if, if, if that were the case along with,
如果，如果，如果是这样的话，
uh, the user's, uh,
呃，用户，呃，
the person's social media data.
该人的社交媒体数据。
And that was the internal data that we did not publish on,
那是我们没有发布的内部数据，
but that we were able to work with clinicians on in
但我们能够与临床医生合作
order to understand if our methods were actually working.
以了解我们的方法是否真正有效。
Um, the external data, the proxy data,
嗯，外部数据，代理数据，
the stuff that we could kinda publish on and talk about,
我们可以发表和谈论的东西，
was based on Twitter.
是基于Twitter的。
Um, and this was, uh,
嗯，这是，恩，
using regular expressions in order to extract, uh,
使用正则表达式来提取，呃，
phases in Twitter feeds that had something that was kind of like diagnoses.
Twitter提要中的某些阶段，这些阶段有点像诊断。
So something like, I've been diagnosed with X,
所以，我被诊断出患有X，
or I've tried to commit suicide.
或者我试图自杀。
And that became kind of the,
这成了一种，
the proxy dataset and the corresponding social media feeds for,
代理数据集和相应的社交媒体提要，
for those individuals, uh,
对那些人来说，呃，
for the actual diagnoses.
用于实际诊断。
Um, and the state-of-the-art in clinical medicine, uh,
嗯，以及临床医学的最新技术，呃，
kind of until this work,
直到这项工作，
there's been more recently but, uh, it's,
最近有，但是，呃，是的，
it's sort of this single task logistic regress- lo- lo- logistic regression setup.
它就是这种单任务逻辑回归 - 逻辑回归设置。
Where you have some input features,
你有一些输入功能，
and then you're making some output predictions like true or false.
然后你做了一些输出预测，如真或假。
Um, you can add some layers and start making it deep learning which is much fancier.
嗯，你可以添加一些图层并开始深入学习，这更加美观。
Um, you can have a bunch of tasks in order to
嗯，你可以拥有一堆任务
do a bunch of logistic regression tasks for a clinical environment.
为临床环境做一堆逻辑回归任务。
Um, or you can use multitask learning, uh,
嗯，或者你可以使用多任务学习，呃，
which is taking the basic deep learning model and adding a bunch of heads to it,
这是采用基本的深度学习模型并添加一堆头，
uh, predicted jointly at the same time.
呃，同时联合预测。
Um, and here we had a bunch of diagnosis data.
嗯，这里我们有一堆诊断数据。
So, um, we predicted things like depression,
那么，嗯，我们预测了抑郁症这样的事情，
anxiety, uh, post-traumatic stress disorder.
焦虑，呃，创伤后应激障碍。
Um, we also added in gender because this is
嗯，我们还添加了性别，因为这是
something that the clinicians told us actually, uh,
临床医生告诉我们的事情，呃，
had some correlation with some of these conditions,
与某些条件有某些相关性，
and that they actually used it in making decisions themselves,
并且他们实际上用它来自己做决定，
for whether or not someone was likely to,
无论是否有人，
uh, attempt, uh, suicide or not.
呃，尝试，呃，自杀与否。
Um, and this also used this idea of comorbidity.
嗯，这也使用了这种合并症的想法。
So multi-task learning is actually kind of perfect for comorbidity in clinical domains.
因此，多任务学习实际上对于临床领域的合并症来说是完美的。
So comorbidity is, um,
所以合并症是，嗯，
when you have one condition,
当你有一个条件时，
you're a lot more likely to have another.
你更有可能拥有另一个。
Um, so people who have
嗯，所以有的人
post-traumatic stress disorder are much more likely to have depression and anxiety.
创伤后应激障碍更容易出现抑郁和焦虑。
Um, and depression and anxiety tend to be cormorbid,
嗯，抑郁和焦虑往往是鸬鹚，
so people who have one often have the other.
所以有一个人经常拥有另一个人。
So this points to the fact- this points to the idea that perhaps there's
所以这指向了这个事实 - 这指向了可能存在的想法
some underlying representation that is similar across them,
一些相似的底层表示，
that can be leveraged in a deep learning model,
可以在深度学习模型中使用，
with individual heads further specifying,
个别负责人进一步指明，
uh, each of the different kinds of conditions.
呃，每种不同的条件。
Um, and so what we found was that as we moved from
嗯，我们发现的是，当我们离开时
logistic regression to the single task deep learning to the multi-task deep learning,
逻辑回归到单任务深度学习到多任务深度学习，
we were able to get significantly better results.
我们得到了明显更好的结果。
And this was true both in the suicide risk case where we had a,
在自杀风险案例中，我们有一个，
a lot of data, as well as
很多数据，以及
the post-traumatic stress disorder case where we had very little data.
创伤后应激障碍的情况，我们的数据非常少。
Um, the behavior here was a little bit different.
嗯，这里的行为有点不同。
So going from logistic regression to,
所以从逻辑回归到
um, single task deep learning,
嗯，单一任务深度学习，
when we had, um,
当我们有，嗯，
a lot of data, uh,
很多数据，呃，
as we did with the suicide risk, um,
正如我们对自杀风险所做的那样，嗯，
had the single task deep learning model
有单一任务深度学习模型
working better than the logistic regression model.
比逻辑回归模型更好地工作。
Um, but when we have very few instances, uh,
嗯，但是当我们的实例很少时，呃，
this is where the deep learning models really struggled a lot more.
这是深度学习模式真正挣扎的地方。
Um, and so the logistic regression models were actually much better.
嗯，因此逻辑回归模型实际上要好得多。
But once we started adding heads for the cormorbid different kinds of conditions,
但是，一旦我们开始为不同种类的条件添加头部，
the different kinds of tasks, um,
不同的任务，嗯，
that related to, you know,
那个与你有关的，
whether or not the person might be committing suicide, um,
该人是否可能自杀，嗯，
we were able to, uh,
我们能够，呃，
bump the accuracy way back up again.
再次提高准确度。
Um, and, it, you know,
嗯，而且，你知道，
it's roughly 120 at-risk individuals that we were able to collect, uh,
这是我们能够收集的大约120个有风险的人，呃，
in the suicide case that we wouldn't have otherwise been able to,
在我们原本无法做到的自杀案中，
to notice as being at risk.
注意到有风险。
Um, one of the approaches we took in this was to
嗯，我们采取的方法之一是
contextualize and consider the ethical dimensions of releasing this kind of technology.
语境化和考虑发布这种技术的道德维度。
So, um, it's really common in NLP papers to give examples.
所以，嗯，在NLP论文中提供例子非常普遍。
Um, but this was an area where we decided that
嗯，但这是我们决定的地方
giving examples of like depressed language,
举出类似沮丧语言的例子，
could be used to discriminate against people,
可以用来歧视人，
like at, you know, job,
就像，你知道，工作，
interviews, or something like that, you know,
面试，或类似的东西，你知道，
the sort of armchair psychology approach.
那种扶手椅心理学方法。
So we decided that while it was important to talk about the technique,
所以我们决定虽然谈论这项技术很重要，
and the utility of multitask learning in
多任务学习的实用性
a clinical domain and for bringing in inclusion of underrepresented subgroups,
临床领域并纳入代表性不足的亚组，
it had to be balanced with the fact that there was a lot of
它必须与有很多事实相平衡
risk in talking about depression,
谈论抑郁症的风险，
and anxiety, and how those kinds of things could be predicted.
和焦虑，以及如何预测这些事情。
Um, so we tried to take a more balanced approach here, um,
嗯，所以我们试着在这里采取更平衡的方法，嗯，
and since then I've been putting ethical considerations in all of my papers.
从那以后，我一直在所有论文中考虑道德问题。
Um, it's becoming more and more common actually.
嗯，它实际上变得越来越普遍。
Um, so another kind of approach that's now turning this on its head,
嗯，所以另一种方法现在正在转变它的头，
where you're trying to remove some effect, um,
在那里你想要消除一些效果，嗯，
mitigate bias in some way,
以某种方式减轻偏见，
is adversarial multi-task learning.
是对抗性的多任务学习。
So I just talked about multi-task learning,
所以我刚才谈到了多任务学习，
and I'll talk about the adversarial case.
我将谈论对抗性案例。
Um, and the idea in the adversarial case is that you have a few heads.
嗯，在对抗案例中的想法是你有几个头。
Um, one is predicting the main task,
嗯，一个人正在预测主要任务，
and the other one is predicting the thing that you don't
另一个是预测你没有的东西
want to be affecting your model's predictions.
想要影响你的模型的预测。
So for example, something like whether or not someone should be promoted based on,
因此，例如，某人是否应该在某人的基础上晋升，
uh, you know, their performance reviews,
呃，你知道，他们的表现评论，
and things like that.
和那样的事情。
Um, you don't want that to be affected by their gender.
嗯，你不希望它受到性别的影响。
Ideally, gender is independent of a promotion decision.
理想情况下，性别与促销决策无关。
And so you can, uh,
所以你可以，呃，
you can create a model for this that actually,
你可以为此创建一个模型，实际上，
uh, puts that independence, um,
呃，把那个独立，嗯，
criteria in place by saying, uh,
说标准，呃，
I want to minimize my loss on the promotion,
我想尽量减少我在促销上的损失，
while maximizing my loss on the gender.
同时最大限度地减少我对性别的损失。
And so how we're doing that is just predicting gender,
所以我们这样做只是预测性别，
and then negating the gradient.
然后否定渐变。
So removing the effect of that signal.
所以消除那个信号的影响。
Um, this is another adversarial approach.
嗯，这是另一种对抗方式。
So you might have been familiar with like generative adversarial networks.
所以你可能已经熟悉了生成对抗网络。
So this is like two discriminators, uh,
所以这就像两个鉴别者，呃，
two different task heads, uh,
两个不同的任务负责人，呃，
where one is trying to do the task that we care about,
一个人试图完成我们关心的任务，
and the other one is removing the signal, uh,
另一个是移除信号，呃，
that we really don't want to,
我们真的不想要，
um, uh, be coming into play in our downstream predictions.
嗯，呃，在我们的下游预测中发挥作用。
Um, so this is a way of,
嗯，所以这是一种方式，
uh, kind of putting this into practice.
呃，有点把它付诸实践。
So the probability of your output,
所以输出的概率，
uh, predicted output given the,
呃，给出的预测输出，
the ground truth and your sensitive attribute like gender, um,
基本事实和你的敏感属性，如性别，嗯，
is equal across all the different, uh,
在所有不同的地方是平等的，呃，
sensitive attributes or equal across all the different genders.
敏感属性或所有不同性别的平等。
Um, and that's an example of equality of opportunity in supervised learning,
嗯，这是监督学习中机会均等的一个例子，
being put into practice.
正在付诸实践。
So this is one of the key fairness definitions.
所以这是关键的公平定义之一。
It's equivalent to, uh,
它相当于，呃，
equal recall across different subgroups as I mentioned earlier.
正如我前面提到的，在不同的小组中进行相等的召回。
Um, and that's a model that will actually,
嗯，这是一个实际的模型，
uh, implement that or help you achieve that.
呃，实现它或帮助你实现这一目标。
Um, where you're saying that a classifier's output decisions should be the same
嗯，你说的是分类器的输出决定应该是相同的
across sensitive characteristics given what the,
跨越敏感特征给出了什么，
what the correct decision should be.
应该做出正确的决定。
Okay, so how are we on time?
好的，我们怎么准时？
Cool. Are there any questions so far? Are we good?
凉。到目前为止有任何问题吗？我们好吗？
Okay, cool. So I'm gonna go into a little bit of a case study now, an end-to-end, uh,
好的，很酷。所以我现在要进行一个案例研究，端到端，呃，
system that Google has been working on, uh,
谷歌一直在努力的系统，呃，
my colleagues have been working on, uh,
我的同事一直在努力，呃，
that is in NLP domain and deals with some of these bias issues.
这是在NLP域中并处理其中一些偏差问题。
Um, so you can find out more about this work, um,
嗯，所以你可以找到更多关于这项工作的信息，嗯，
in papers at AIES in 2018 and FAT* tutorial 2019,
在2018年的AIES和FAT * 2019年的教学论文中，
um, called Measuring and Mitigating Unintended Bias in Text Classification.
嗯，称为测量和减轻文本分类中的意外偏差。
Um, and this came out of Conversation-AI which is a, uh,
嗯，这来自Conversation-AI，这是一个，呃，
which is a product that's, um,
这是一种产品，嗯，
like it's part of this- it's called a bet at Google.
喜欢它的一部分 - 它被称为谷歌赌注。
It's a kind of spin-off company called Jigsaw that
它是一种名为Jigsaw的衍生公司
focuses on trying to like combat abuse online.
专注于尝试在线滥用战斗滥用。
Um, and the Conversation-AI, uh,
嗯，对话-AI，呃，
team is trying to use deep learning to improve online conversations.
团队正在尝试使用深度学习来改善在线对话。
Um, and collaborate with a ton of different,
嗯，和很多不同的人合作，
uh, different people to do that.
呃，不同的人这样做。
Um, so how this works is,
嗯，这是如何工作的，
oh you can try it out too, on perspectiveapi.com.
哦，你也可以尝试一下，在perspectiveapi.com上。
So given some phrase like you're a dork, uh,
所以给出一些像你是笨蛋的短语，呃，
it puts out a toxicity score associated to that like 0,91. [NOISE]
它得出与0,91相关的毒性评分。 [噪声]
Um, and the model starts sort of falsely associating
嗯，模型开始有点虚假关联
frequently attacked identities with toxicity.
经常攻击具有毒性的身份。
So this is a kind of false positive bias.
所以这是一种误报的偏见。
So I'm a proud tall person gets a model,
所以我是一个自豪的高个子得到一个模特，
uh, toxicity score of 0,18.
呃，毒性评分为0,18。
I'm a proud, uh,
我很自豪，呃，
gay person gets a toxicity model score of 0,69.
同性恋者的毒性模型得分为0,69。
And this is because these- the term gay tends to be used in really toxic situations.
这是因为这些 - 同性恋这个词往往被用于真正有毒的情况。
And so the model starts to learn that gay itself is toxic.
因此模型开始了解同性恋本身是有毒的。
But that's not actually what we want,
但那实际上并不是我们想要的，
and we don't want these kinds of predictions coming out of the model.
我们不希望这种类型的预测来自模型。
Um, so, uh, the bias is largely caused here by the dataset imbalance.
嗯，呃，这种偏差很大程度上是由数据集失衡导致的。
Again, this is data kinda coming and wearing its hat again.
再一次，这是数据有点再次戴上帽子。
Um, so frequently attacked, uh,
嗯，经常受到攻击，呃，
identities are really overrepresented in toxic comments.
在有毒评论中，身份确实过多。
There's a lot of toxicity towards LGBTQ identities, um,
对LGBTQ身份有很多毒性，嗯，
it's really horrible to work on this stuff that like
在这些喜欢的东西上工作真的太可怕了
really [LAUGHTER] it can really affect you personally.
真的[笑声]它真的会影响到你个人。
Um, uh, and, uh,
嗯，呃，呃，
one of the approaches that the team took was just to add nontoxic data from Wikipedia.
团队采取的方法之一就是添加来自维基百科的无毒数据。
So helping to- helping the model to understand that these kinds of terms can be used in,
因此，帮助模型理解可以使用这些术语，
you know, more positive sorts of contexts.
你知道，更积极的背景。
One of the challenges with measuring, uh,
测量的挑战之一，呃，
how well the system was doing is that there's not
系统的表现如何，就是没有
a really nice way to have controlled toxicity evaluation.
一种控制毒性评估的非常好的方法。
Um, so in real-world conversation,
嗯，所以在现实世界的对话中，
it can be kind of anyone's guess what the toxicity is of a specific sentence.
任何人都可以猜出特定句子的毒性是什么。
Um, if you really wanna control for a different kind of
嗯，如果你真的想要控制另一种
subgroups or intersectional subgroups,
亚组或交叉子组，
and it can be even harder to get, uh,
它可能更难获得，呃，
a real good data to evaluate properly.
一个真正好的数据来正确评估。
So what the team ended up doing was developing a synthetic data approach.
所以团队最终做的是开发一种合成数据方法。
Um, so this is kind of like a bias Mad Libs.
嗯，所以这有点像偏见疯狂的自由人。
Um, where you take template sentences [NOISE], um,
嗯，你拿模板句[NOISE]，嗯，
and you use those for evaluation. This is the kind of, um,
并使用它们进行评估。这是那种，嗯，
evaluation you'd want to use in addition to your target downstream
除目标下游之外，您还想使用的评估
ah, kind of dataset.
啊，那种数据集。
But this helps you get at the biases specifically.
但这有助于您明确了解偏见。
So, um, some template phrase like I am a proud blank person,
所以，嗯，一些模板短语，比如我是一个自豪的空白人，
and then filling in different subgroup identities.
然后填写不同的子组标识。
And you don't want to release the model unless you see that
除非你看到，否则你不想发布模型
the scores across these different kinds of, uh,
这些不同种类的分数，呃，
these different kinds of template sentences with synthetic, uh,
这些不同类型的模板句子用合成的，呃，
the synthetic template sentences, um,
合成模板句子，嗯，
are relatively kind of the same across, ah, yeah.
相对来说是相同的啊，是啊。
All of the different model runs.
所有不同的模型运行。
Cool. Um, so some assumptions that they made in this was that the dataset, um, uh,
凉。嗯，所以他们在这做的一些假设是数据集，嗯，呃，
didn't have annotated bias and they didn't do
没有注释偏见，他们没有做
any causal analysis because they were just trying to focus in particular,
任何因果分析，因为他们只是特别关注，
um, on this toxicity problem.
嗯，关于这个毒性问题。
Um, they used the CNN,
嗯，他们使用CNN，
ah, convolutional, yeah you guys know, blah, blah, blah.
啊，卷积，是的，你们都知道，等等，等等，等等。
Uh, with pretrained chain GloVe embeddings.
呃，有预训练链GloVe嵌入。
This is probably like your bread and butter.
这可能就像你的面包和黄油。
Pretrained GloVe embeddings.
预训练GloVe嵌入。
I'm sure you know all about this in Word2vec.
我相信你在Word2vec中知道这一切。
Cool, uh, Keras implementation of this.
很酷，呃，Keras实现这个。
Um, and, uh, and using these kind of data augmentation approaches, um,
嗯，呃，并且使用这些数据增强方法，嗯，
both a Wikipedia, uh,
维基百科，呃，
kind of approach as well as actually collecting positive statements about LGBTQ identity.
这种方法以及实际收集关于LGBTQ身份的积极陈述。
So there's this project called Project Respect at Google,
所以这个项目名为Project Respect at Google，
where we go out and,
我们出去的地方，
and talk to people who identify as queer or people who have friends who do,
和那些认同酷儿的人或有朋友的人交谈，
and like talk about this in a positive way,
并以积极的方式谈论这个，
and we add this as data.
我们将其添加为数据。
Um, so we can actually know that this is can be a positive thing.
嗯，所以我们实际上可以知道这可能是一件好事。
Um, and in order to measure the model performance here, um,
嗯，为了衡量这里的模特表现，嗯，
again it's looking at the differences across different subgroups and trying to
再次，它正在考虑不同子群体之间的差异并尝试
compare also the subgroup performance to some sort of general distribution.
将子组性能与某种一般分布进行比较。
So here they use AUC, um,
所以他们在这里使用AUC，嗯，
where AUC is essentially the probability that a model will
其中AUC基本上是模型的概率
give a randomly sel- selected positive example,
给出一个随机选择的正面例子，
a higher score than a randomly selected, uh, negative example.
得分高于随机选择的呃负面例子。
So, um, here you can see some toxic comments and
所以，嗯，在这里你可以看到一些有毒的评论和
nontoxic comments with a example sort of low AUC.
具有低AUC示例的无毒评论。
Um, here, ah, this is an
嗯，这里啊，这是一个
example with a high AUC,
AUC高的例子，
so the model is doing a relatively good job of separating these two kinds of comments.
所以该模型在分离这两种评论方面做得相对较好。
Um, and there are different kinds of biases that they've defined in this work.
嗯，他们在这项工作中定义了不同类型的偏见。
So, uh, low subgroup performance means that
所以，呃，低子群表现意味着
the model performs worse on subgroup comments than it does,
该模型在子组注释上的表现比它更差，
ah, on comments overall.
啊，总体评论。
And the metric they've introduced to measure this is called subgroup AUC.
他们为衡量这一点而引入的指标称为子组AUC。
Um, another one is subgroup shift.
嗯，另一个是小组转移。
And that's when the model systematically scores comments,
当模型系统地评分评论时，
um, from some subgroup higher.
嗯，来自某个较高的小组。
Um, so this is sort of like to the right.
嗯，所以这有点像右边。
Um, and then there's also, uh,
嗯，然后还有，呃，
this Background Positive Subgroup Negative shifting to the left.
此背景正子组向左移位负向。
Yeah. Um, yeah that's sort of saying what I said.
是啊。嗯，是的，这就是我说的话。
It can go either way to the right or the left and there's just
它可以向右或向左移动，而且只是
kind of different metrics that can define each of these.
可以定义其中每一种的不同指标。
Cool. Um, and the results in this,
凉。嗯，结果在这，
ah, sort of going through not only just looking at, you know,
啊，有点经历，不仅仅是看，你知道，
qualitative examples, um, and general evaluation metrics,
定性示例，嗯和一般评估指标，
but also focusing in on some of the key metrics defined for this work,
但也关注为这项工作定义的一些关键指标，
these sort of AUC-based approaches.
这些基于AUC的方法。
And they were able to see significant differences in
他们能够看到显着的差异
the original release which didn't account for any of these unintended biases,
原始版本没有考虑到任何这些非预期的偏见，
and downstream releases, uh, which did,
和下游版本，呃，哪个，
which incorporated this kind of normative data
其中包含了这种规范性数据
that said the sort of things that we thought the model should be learning.
那就是说我们认为模型应该学习的东西。
Cool. Um, so, um,
凉。嗯，恩，嗯，
the last thing to keep in mind as you sort of develop and,
在你开发的时候要记住的最后一件事，
and work towards, uh, creating deeper better models is to release responsibly.
并且努力创造更深层次的更好的模型是负责任地发布。
Um, so this is a project I've been working on with
嗯，所以这是我一直在努力的项目
a ton of different people called Model Cards for Model Reporting.
大量不同的人称为模型报告模型卡。
It's, uh, it's a little bit of like the next step after Datasheets for Datasets,
这是，呃，它有点像Datasheets for Datasets之后的下一步，
um, where, um, Datasheets for Datasets focuses on information about the data.
嗯，其中，嗯，Datasheets for Datasets专注于有关数据的信息。
Ah, Model Cards for Model Reporting focuses on information about the model.
啊，模型报告模型卡侧重于有关模型的信息。
Um, so it captures what it does,
嗯，它抓住了它的作用，
how it works, why it matters.
它是如何工作的，为什么重要。
Um, and one of the key ideas here is disaggregated in intersectional evaluation.
嗯，这里的一个关键想法是在交叉评估中分解的。
So it's not enough, uh,
所以这还不够，呃，
any more to put out human-centered technology that just
再推出以人为本的技术
has some vague overall score associated to it.
有一些模糊的总分与之相关。
You actually need to understand how it works across different subpopulations.
实际上，您需要了解它在不同子群体中的工作原理。
And you have to understand what the data is telling you that.
而且您必须了解数据告诉您的内容。
Um, so here's some example details that a
嗯，所以这里有一些例子细节
model card would have,
模型卡会有，
um, who it's developed by,
嗯，它是由谁开发的，
what the intended use is,
用途是什么，
so that it doesn't start being used in ways that it's not intended to be used.
因此它不会以不打算使用的方式开始使用。
Um, the factors that are likely to be
嗯，可能是因素
affected by disproportionate performance of the model.
受到模型不成比例的影响。
Um, so different kinds of identity groups, things like that.
嗯，不同种类的身份群体，这样的事情。
Um, the metrics that, ah,
嗯，指标啊，
that you're deciding to use in order to understand the fairness of the model or
您决定使用以了解模型的公平性或
the different performance of the model across different kinds of subgroups and factors,
不同类型的子群和因子的模型的不同表现，
information about the evaluation data and training data.
有关评估数据和培训数据的信息。
Um, as well as ethical considerations, um,
嗯，还有道德方面的考虑，嗯，
so what were some of the things you took into
那么你接受了什么呢？
account or what are some of the risks and benefits,
帐户或有哪些风险和收益，
um, that, uh, that are relevant to this model?
嗯，那个，呃，与这个模型有关吗？
Um, and additional caveats and recommendations.
嗯，还有其他警告和建议。
So for example, in the conversation AI case,
例如，在对话AI案例中，
they're working with synthetic data.
他们正在使用合成数据。
So this is the sort of limitation of the evaluation that's important to understand, uh,
所以这是评估的一种限制，这对理解很重要，呃，
because it can tell you a lot about the biases,
因为它可以告诉你很多偏见，
but doesn't tell you a lot about how it works generally.
但是并没有告诉你一般它是如何工作的。
[NOISE] And then the key component in the quantitative,
[NOISE]然后是定量的关键组成部分，
uh, section of the model card is to have
呃，模型卡的部分是有的
this both intersectional and disaggregated evaluation.
这是交叉和分解的评估。
And from here, you trivially get to different kinds of fairness definitions.
从这里开始，您可以轻松地获得不同类型的公平定义。
The closer you get to parity across subgroups,
你越接近亚组的平价，
the closer you're getting to something that is mathematically fair.
你越接近数学上公平的东西。
Okay. So hopefully by paying attention to these kinds of approaches,
好的。希望通过关注这些方法，
taking into account all these kinds of things,
考虑到所有这些事情，
we can move from majority representation of data in
我们可以从数据的多数表示转移到
our models to something more like diverse representation,
我们的模型更像是多样化的表现形式，
uh, from our ethical AI.
呃，来自我们的道德AI。
Okay. That's it.
好的。而已。
Thanks. [APPLAUSE]
谢谢。 [掌声]